santanderbank.com 2014-02-09

# Privacy Policy - Santander

This Privacy Notice, effective October 17, 2013, is being provided to you to describe what Santander Bank, N. A. does to keep information about you private and secure, and how we manage that information. As described below, you also have a choice about how your information is shared. This Notice also covers divisions of Santander Bank, such as Nantucket Bank and Bank of Martha’s Vineyard.

**What does Santander do with your personal information?**

**  
WHY?  
**Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.

**WHAT?  
**The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include:

  * Social Security number and income
  * Account balances and payment history
  * Credit history and credit scores

We may share any of the categories of customer information with companies that work for us, including companies located outside the United States. When you close your account, we continue to share information about you according to our policies.

**NOTE:** We may disclose all the kinds of information described in this section to companies we hire to perform marketing services on our behalf, or to other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements, such as insurance companies and brokerage firms. We refer to these companies as “marketing partners.” Please note that, should you decide to take advantage of such an offer from one of our marketing partners, you will become a customer of our marketing partner for that product offering, and will be subject to the terms of our marketing partner’s privacy policy.

**HOW?  
**All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business—to process transactions, maintain customer accounts, and report to credit bureaus. In the section below, we list reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the information Santander chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.

**Reasons we can share your personal information** | **Does Santander  
share?** | **Can you limit  
this sharing?**  
---|---|---  
For our everyday business purposes—to process your transactions, maintain your account, and report to  
credit bureaus | Yes | No  
For our marketing purposes—to offer our products and services to you | Yes | No*  
For joint marketing with other financial companies | Yes | No*  
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes—information about your transactions and experiences | Yes | No  
For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes—information about your creditworthiness | Yes | Yes  
For our affiliates to market their products or services to you | Yes | Yes  
For nonaffiliates to market non-financial institutions’ products or services to you | No | n/a  
  
**To limit our sharing** | 

  * Call 1-877-768-2265** - our menu will prompt you through your choice(s) or
  * Visit us [online](https://apply.santanderbank.com/personal/forms/privacy_prefs.asp) to limit sharing of your information

Please note:  
If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information (30) days from the date we sent this notice.  
When you are no longer our customer, we can continue to share your information as described in this notice.  
However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  
---|---  
**Questions?** | Call 1-877-768-2265** or go to [www.santanderbank.com](http://www.santanderbank.com/)  
  
*Although the sharing of this information cannot be limited, you may let us know whether or not you wish to be contacted for marketing purposes.  
**For customers with hearing impairments, please call 1-800-428-9121 (TTY/TDD)

**SPECIAL NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA AND VERMONT RESIDENTS:** If your account has a California mailing address, we will not market any products or services to you, nor will we share your information with our marketing partners for them to market to you. If your account has a Vermont mailing address, we will share with our marketing partners only that information that is permitted by law. Residents of California and Vermont do not have to take any further action to limit the sharing of information; such limits are already in place. 

**Sharing Practices**

**How does Santander  
protect my personal  
information?** | To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that  
comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.  
Employees have access to your information on a need-to-know basis to perform their job function.  
Santander or its service providers may also use tracer technology, which are third-party cookies. If  
you are uncomfortable with our use of cookie technology, you can set your browser to refuse cookies.  
However, some of our services depend on cookies and you may not be able to use those services by  
refusing cookies.  
---|---  
**How does Santander  
collect my personal  
information?** | We collect your personal information, for example, when you 

  * Open an account or deposit money
  * Pay your bills or apply for a loan
  * Use your credit card or debit card

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates,  
or other companies.  
For online and mobile banking customers, we may use cookies, which are pieces of data that help web  
sites recognize return visitors, to personalize and enrich your online visits with us and to collect site  
visitation statistics.  
**Why can’t I limit  
all sharing?** | Federal law gives you the right to limit only 

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your creditworthiness
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.  
**What happens when  
I limit sharing for an  
account I hold jointly  
with someone else?** | Your choices will apply to everyone on your account.  
  
**NOTE:** We may share certain customer information with government and consumer reporting agencies as permitted or required by such laws as the Federal Right to Financial Privacy Act. These disclosures are usually made for your benefit and for specific circumstances, for example, verifying identities to reduce fraud and identity theft or for prompt credit approval or as required by law, such as in response to a subpoena or court order.

**Definitions**

**Affiliates/Subsidiaries** | Our affiliates include companies with the word “Santander” in their name. This includes financial  
companies such as Banco Santander, S.A., Santander Puerto Rico, Santander Holdings USA, Inc.  
Santander Consumer USA, Santander Securities LLC and Santander Insurance Agency U.S. LLC.  
---|---  
**Nonaffiliates** | Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and non-financial  
companies.

_We do not share customer information with nonaffiliated companies except in the very limited circumstances  
specifically permitted by law._  
  
**Joint marketing** | A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products  
or services to you.

_Our joint marketing partners include credit card and insurance companies. The formal agreement includes  
assurances by the marketing partner that they will maintain the appropriate safeguards to ensure the  
security and confidentiality of the information we provide to them, and that the information may only be  
used within the confines of the stated agreement._  
  
**Your Preferences  
**How to contact us:

  * **Toll Free (Sin Cargo): 1.877.768.2265**

Santander Bank  
Bank of Martha’s Vineyard

  * **Toll Free (Sin Cargo): 1.800.533.9313**

Nantucket Bank only

  * **On the web:**

  * **Visit one of our branches**

**NOTE:** If you have already contacted Santander with your marketing preferences, regarding sharing information about your creditworthiness or sharing information with affiliates for marketing purposes, it is not necessary to do so again, unless you wish to change your preferences. Your preferences will remain in force until you change them in writing at a branch, or by e-mailing our online preference management system. They will be honored even if you close your account, according to our policies. Your e-mail preference will apply only to the e-mail address(es) we have on record for you. Your telephone preference will apply only to the telephone number we have on record for you. Requests will be processed in a timely manner, not to exceed thirty days.

**FOR NEVADA RESIDENTS:** At any time, you may request to be placed on Santander’s internal do not call list by following the instructions in the “Your Preferences” section above. Nevada law also requires that we provide you with the following information: Santander Bank, Mail Code: RI1-EPV-02-18, 95 Amaral Street, East Providence, RI, 02915 and Bureau of Consumer Protection, Office of the Nevada Attorney General, 555 East Washington Avenue, Suite 3900, Las Vegas, NV 89101, Phone: 702.486.3132, E-mail: [bcpinfo@ag.state.nv.us](mailto:bcpinfo@ag.state.nv.us).
